I found myself lost and alone on this journey
Though my heart wandered far and wide, I could move not an inch
But now I can depart for any distant land
Now that we've met on this road
Even the unfamiliar songs of travelers
Can spark nostalgia in me when I'm with you
If the world we dreamed of exists somewhere,
Then let's go search for it beyond the wind
Through chilling dawns,
Through arid noons,
Through shivering nights,
Let's go see what lies at the end
You must be in the middle of a deal since you've come at a time like this.
Need a certificate?
Yes.
I hope you become a merchant who'll intimidate his clientele by name alone in the near future.
My thoughts exactly.
Oh, by the way, would you happen to know anyone who'd like to travel to Lamtra?
Geez, it seems like everyone here falls for the same trap.
Dazzled by a certain young shepherdess, eh?
No, I...
She's the only person who wanders that area unscathed.
I don't think I have to tell you what the Church thinks about that.
Don't involve yourself with her if you don't want to find yourself in a mess.
Norah the Fairy does seem to be your type of girl, though.
G-Give me a break.
Who do I make the certificate out to? Or should I leave it blank?
Make it out to Lemerio Trading, please
You already have a buyer... Did you purchase on credit or something?
Yes. Is that a bad thing?
Oh, you'll find out soon enough.
Did any major price fluctuations occur?
No, there's no reason to worry too much.
I'm sure you of all people will be able to turn it to your advantage.
Oh, and wait a bit before letting any pretty girls ensnare you, y'hear?
They'll soak up all your profits just like that!
I wouldn't invest if I didn't anticipate returns.
Hahaha! Is that so?
Here's the certificate.
Thank you very much.
Please wish me lots of luck.
Wolf and Conspiracies
Sorry to keep you waiting, Holo.
They were precious. Called me a pretty little snowdrop, they did.
They're no different from hungry dogs. Don't bother with them or they might take you away.
If I'm kidnapped, you'll just have to rescue me again.
Am I wrong?
Sure, I'd rescue you.
Of course, in the end, I was the one who rescued you.
Well, I don't know what kind of return you're expecting,
but go ahead and invest to your heart's content.
You heard all that?
I didn't know you liked blondes.
Are you attracted to her scrawny appearance? Or do you like the way her cares are etched on her face?
Or do you just have a thing for shepherdesses?
Wait a second! He and I were just shooting the breeze. I'm not—
You're not what?
W-Well, sure, I thought Norah was nice.
I can't say our conversation wasn't fun.
But that doesn't mean I don't care about you, or—well, it doesn't mean that!
Well... I was just trying to tease you a little...
But...
I didn't expect you to take it so seriously.
I'm happy.
Holo...
However,
males simply say whatever's convenient.
I'm a merchant.
I'm a man of my word.
I know that knights entrust their shields and swords as proof of sincerity.
What can you entrust to me as a merchant?
Very well. I'll prove my sincerity to you.
I'll buy you peaches preserved in honey—
Hmm? What will you buy me?
You can't do that! You're crossing the line!
You said I should ask more charmingly.
I said you should ask nicely!
Not to use your feminine wiles!
Didn't you think I was cute, though?
My heart was racing more from your reaction than from worrying about whether my scheme would work.
Come on, now. Don't be so upset.
I was happy to hear you say that, truly.
Are you angry all the same?
All right. I'm not upset, okay? I'm not upset.
Are you satisfied?
It won't do to get separated.
May I take your hand?
Yeah, losing sight of you would cause problems.
In any case, business is scary.
You need to use your head in order to make money,
but if you go too far and your plans fail,
you'll end up like Latparon Trading and be forced to sell goods at half the price.
But if you do it right,
you could make huge profits with something simple, like moving armor on margin.
That's the essence of business.
But the fact that you're in debt doesn't sit well with me, even if it is temporary.
Are you talking about buying on credit?
That's right.
You bought a hundred Lumione worth of armor at half price, which means you're in debt to Latparon, right?
Yeah, I'll sell them to Lemerio Trading at market price, and
my debt will be settled between the two trading companies.
I'm dealing with double my net worth, so the profit I make will be double what it would normally be.
Isn't it worth the worry even if you're not fond of the idea?
Well, you might be right.
Is this place run by a friar?
We'd be hearing the sound of prayers if that were the case.
I bet you can't hear a thing over the sound of chewing my meat pie.
You have a fine sense of wry humor,
but for the sake of my reputation, I'll tell you that I can hear the sound of someone in the building.
There are people inside?
Indeed. But the atmosphere's unpleasant,
and it's definitely not lively in there.
Hesitating won't get me anywhere...
We can't make money if we don't sell the goods.
And a meat pie's no good unless you eat it.
I was saving that, you know.
Oh? If you wanted some, you should have asked.
Here.
There's still some time left before the sabbath.
Did something unusual happen?
Well, something like that.
Did you just arrive today, sir?
No, I came here a few days ago.
You know how it goes.
I can see that you're rather popular, sir.
Not at all.
Well, excuse me.
I see.
I look forward to seeing you again,
Craft Lawrence-san.
It's as I thought.
I see that you've brought armor from Latparon Trading with you.
How did you know?
Actually, we were notified by a messenger on horseback.
Latparon Trading assigned the debt to us.
They transferred the debt?!
What's going on?
Your companion has failed miserably at business.
Just as we have.
What?
The armor market crashed a while ago, and it's worth almost nothing now.
Latparon let him borrow money towards worthless stock and transferred the rights to our company.
Long story short, your companion was left with only his monstrous debt.
In other words, he's bankrupt.
You've...
I was tricked...
We both live by such agreements.
I'm sure you understand.
Of course, Lemerio-san. I'm a merchant, after all.
Lawrence-san, you purchased one hundred Lumione worth of arms from Latparon Trading.
Out of that, forty-seven and three-fourths Lumione was financed with debt—and a due date.
I request immediate payment of your financial obligations.
We will have to ask the Lohen Trading Union to assume your debt if you cannot pay.
Understood.
Well, the deadline for payment is the day after tomorrow, so we'll wait two days
for you to return the forty-seven and 3/4 Lumione.
I'll find a way to sell the armor for a high price.
We'll settle the balance in two days. Will that do?
Yes.
Well then, I'll get going.
Just to let you know,
we do have open air vendors at every town gate that can certainly fulfill any of your needs.
Please do not hesitate to make use of them.
I appreciate the offer, but I think I'll respectfully decline
since you'll probably be busy enough with other customers.
I look forward to seeing you in two days.
May God be with you.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
So...
Explain what happened in there.
Basically, the merchandise we're carrying has turned into scrap.
Then I suppose I didn't hear wrong.
This could mean bankruptcy for me.
Should we run?
The information networks among merchants are like the eyes of God.
If I tried to do business anywhere, I'd be found out immediately.
I'd never be able to work as a merchant again.
But wounded animals are eaten to the bone.
Will you accept that fate?
Who said I'd do that?
I just need to return forty-seven Lumione gold coins.
It shouldn't be too difficult to make ends meet.
I'm Holo, the wise wolf.
I'll certainly help in any way I can.
You could help me a great deal by cutting back on the amount you eat every—
I said all along I'd pay for my own food.
I was kidding.
If you can joke, you'll be fine.
If worse comes to worst, upon my honor, I will help you escape...
even if I must use the power within the wheat.
You promised to take me to the northern woods.
I can't have you getting tripped up here.
I'll keep that promise, and...
If it comes to it, I may need saving.
Okay. Count on it.
I'll stop by the trading house for now.
Wait for me at the inn—
Do I look like the kind of ungrateful wolf that would groom her tail and let her companion face a crisis alone?
No, but...
Do I look like that kind of wolf?
No, you don't.
But that's not the point.
Then what is the point?
The trading house is like home for us merchants.
You understand what bringing a girl home means, right?
Why can't you simply explain the situation?
How do you expect me to do that?
I wouldn't know what to do if they reported you to the Church.
In that case, just tell them we're lovers or something!
All right.
You can come with me.
You're more quick-witted than I am anyway.
Indeed. Leave it to me.
But I'll tell them that you're a business associate.
You don't need to say anything beyond that.
Okay.
That bunch can give a rough welcome.
Don't you worry about me.
First off, I want to know who this lovely lady might be.
She's a business partner. We're traveling together.
Business?
She single-handedly increased the value of my marten furs
from 140 to 210 Trenni coins at the Milone Trading in Pazzio.
What?
I did say this morning that I'd see a return from investing in her.
Pairs like you show up ever so often.
Well, whatever.
The scriptures say not to carelessly open a mysterious box.
A wise decision.
Well...
Let's move on to the main topic.
A man from Lemerio Trading just came to talk to us about
assuming your debt, so I have a general idea of what's going on.
In short, you got greedy and had the rug pulled out from under you, correct?
Yes.
That makes things rather simple.
You yourself must pay back the debt that this guild, in all likelihood, will be faced with.
If you were swindled, robbed, or suffered losses due to illness or injury,
then upon our honor, we would have helped you. But not this time.
The only one who can save you is God—or this beauty.
I'm fully aware of that.
Unfortunately, I'm not in a position where I can show you any compassion.
It's because I know the need to be strict at times like this that I get to stay in that gathering hall.
The Union's laws bind us all.
Of course.
I'd be as upset as anyone if a member were treated as an exception to the rule.
Loans among Union members aren't allowed, either.
I'm aware of that.
Your obligation comes due in two days, correct?
Lemerio is burdened by their own failed armor investments.
They won't hesitate to demand payment.
In other words, your failure will be made public the day after tomorrow, and I'll have to detain you.
What do you think will happen at that time?
There won't be a future for me unless I come up with forty-seven Lumione within two days.
It's not that you won't have a future.
There will be a fate that awaits you.
But it will be one that is black, bitter, and heavy.
You could pay back a debt of forty-seven Lumione in ten years by rowing a long-distance ship.
You could also work in a mine.
If you're lucky enough to survive that long, of course.
A nightmare come to life.
Don't forget, though.
It's not that I want to see you die.
Sins must be punished. It's my duty to enforce that simple principle.
I understand.
Do what you can in the next two days.
If you need my help with business, I'll do whatever I can.
I have faith in you.
Go out there and give it your best shot.
I appreciate your concern.
I'll find a way to manage in two days, somehow.
There are always possibilities in business—and some you can only see when you are in true danger.
Is there anything else you'd like to say or ask?
No.
Excuse us.
There is one thing.
You should start thinking about what to say when I repay my debts.
If you can still talk like that, you'll be fine.
I'll see you soon.
Forty-seven Lumione in two days, huh?
What are you going to do?
I'll divide the debt into smaller debts for the time being.
Do you have people you can borrow from?
I'm a businessman, you know.
I don't know anyone who'll lend me a substantial amount of money, but I do know a lot of people I could ask.
It'll be easy if you can find forty-seven people.
Exactly.
Oh, Lawrence-san. Long time no see!
Have you brought me talk of profit?
Well, to tell you the truth...
I've barely started. There are still plenty of people I can ask.
Unfortunately, I'm stretched pretty thin at the moment.
Prices for wheat and meat will increase as we head into the new year.
How did things go?
There's always the next one.
That's right.
I have to stock items for the upcoming spring.
Sorry, but I can't.
How about we...
Damn! Why? Why did I make that deal?
You idiot!
Are you...
It's nothing.
On to the next one.
What about there? No, that's pointless.
Wait. Hold on!
What is it?
Sorry, but I can't walk as fast as I'd like to in this form.
No, it's my fault.
It's been a while, Lawrence-san.
Likewise.
I apologize for coming after the market has closed.
I'd like to ask you for a favor.
I heard you've been making requests all over.
Is it because the armor market has crashed?
Yes.
I made a mistake due to my lack of foresight.
Lack of foresight? That might be.
God is the only one who can predict the prices of commodities, though.
It'd be cruel to criticize someone on that alone.
Lawrence-san, I've had many opportunities to make money thanks to you.
I've thought about helping you out if there was ever a time you were in need.
Then...
But you don't seem like a man who diligently lives according
to the teachings of God or is earnestly seeking relief.
U-Um...
What do you mean by that?
You have the audacity to come with a girl in tow at a time you're desperately relying on people's goodwill?
You idiot! Don't just wander into the middle of the street!
Why... Why is this happening to me?
Why?
Hey! Are you okay?
You're so pale!
Let's go back to the inn and—
If it wasn't for you...
Sorry.
I'm going back first.
Next Episode, "Wolf and the Grand Scheme."